Why did it take three decades for
Cypress Hill, one of the most iconic
Latin hip hop groups, to release their
first full-on Spanish language album?
With the movement's Latino roots in New
York City, acts like Kid Frost, Mellow
Man Ace, and even Vico C came along and
started rapping in English, Spanish, and
even Spanglish. Cypress Hill's 1991
self-titled album was a game-changer,
leaning into the West Coast Latino
experience with powerful lyrics and a
flow that was both assertive and suave.
The band recently put out Dos Equis
Cerveza, full Spanish language album
filled with songs like the cool cumbia
of Campeones.
>> [music]
>> You know, releasing a Spanish language
album 35 years after planting a flag for
Latino culture in hip hop could be seen
as kind of strange, you know? Why now?
But after talking to the guys for the
Alt Latino podcast, it's very clear to
me it's just another reason why they are
the icons that they are. They're
following their own artistic vision at
their own pace, and we can go along for
the ride and just enjoy. You can check
out the full conversation with Cypress
Hill on Alt Latino wherever you get your
podcast.